

Bengaluru +91 9448089777

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING | DEVOPS | CLOUD NATIVE | EMPHATHETIC LEADERSHIP

# **Executive Summary**

Over 20+ years of IT experience, 10+ years of software development using Java & other Open source platforms/frameworks, 10+ years of Managing global teams in Product Organizations creating DevOps culture, setting up CI/CD pipelines & developing loosely coupled self-healing distributed fault tolerant applications for multi-cloud platforms. Diversified background in Application development, Automation, building Infrastructure & Configuration As Code, creating DevOps Tools roadmap & implementing DevSecOps pipelines and managing K8s deployments across large clusters (Public & SAP proprietary datacenters) using declarative kustomized GitOps Toolsets. Excellent Team player, recognized for building global delivery teams and consistently popular people manager in employee surveys. Combines organizational business acumen with analytical depth. personable with strong written and verbal communications skills.

#### **Skills & Abilities**

- Kubernetes(CKA & CKAD)
- Azure & AWS DevOps
- Everything as Code
- People & Stakeholder Mgmnt
- DevSecOps Strategy
- GitOps & SRE
- Skill Development
- Agile & Scrum Approach
- Cloud Native App Design
- CI, Automation & Pipeline
- **Escalation Management**
- Jenkins, Ansible, Terraform

## **Experience**

#### FREELANCE TECH CONSULTANT | DEVOPS COACH | OCT 2022-TILL DATE & APR 2018 - MAR 2021

- As a Technology Expert, involved in various consulting & coaching engagements in areas relating to Application Development, Cloud Migration, DevSecOps adoption & SRE activities, along with handling Leadership & Technology Coaching & Training workshops relating to DevOps best practices
- · Cloud Migration consultant for a Health care start-up www.Right-Nutrition.com responsible for migrating applications to Cloud platforms and setting up K8s Cluster on AWS/Azure, configuring K8s cluster with various components - Lets Encrypt (TLS), Consul, Traefik & NGINX Ingress, setting up Observability & Metrics
- Conducted various Tech workshops & hands-on Corp Training sessions for DevOps tools such as Git (GitHub, BitBucket, GitLab), Jenkins, Docker, Ansible & K8s Certifications, for customers like Ericsson, Walmart Labs, Dell, Viacom 18, Standard Chartered, Credit Suisse, Nissan, Accenture, GE, Daimler/Benz, Times Group etc

# DEVLELOPMENT MANAGER | SAP LABS, BENGALURU | APR 2021 – SEPT 2022 SAP SuccessFactors 💛



- · Lead Microservice Delivery & DevOps Automation teams at SAP SuccessFactors
- · Develop & Support Cloud Automation & GitOps Microservice release pipelines across 25+ Datacenters for multiple HXM product lines covering primarily BizX, LMS & Mobile microservices
- · Driving Automation using tools such as Azure Repos & Pipeline, ArgoCD, piper-Jenkins, Terraform, Ansible & Chef Inspec, implementing guard-rails for both Helm & Kustomized deployments using various Admission Controllers, liaising with SAP Central Infosec teams for DevSecops initiatives (StackRox & OWASP ZAP Scans, Dockerfile lints & other quality gates, Splunk, Zabbix & Dynatrace ) and supporting other tools (Vault, external secrets, Consul etc)

#### SENIOR MANAGER, IT APPLICATIONS | BROCADE COMMUNICATIONS | SEP 2011 - MAR 2018

- Recruited to build and lead off-shore Application development initiatives of Brocade IT Team @Bangalore, I have been responsible for managing implementations of complex and large scale IT projects involving distributed development teams including FTEs & Vendors/CWs
- Few milestone projects that were successfully delivered MyBrocade Transformation (<u>promo video</u>) which involved complete UI/UX makeover for our product management & provisioning portal MyBrocade,
  Implementation of a highly available, and scalable Big Data analytics solution, hosted on AWS, Quality Data Reporting to assist Brocade manufacturing team to analyze large (approx. 30-50K logs per day) diagnostic logs (> 15MB each) in near real time and run complex business rules using Twitter Storm MapReduce jobs

## SOLUTION ARCHITECT | LOGICA CMG | NOV 2008 - AUG 2011

· Part of Logica's Product Engineering Team and was involved in various technology consultation engagements for modernizing applications, implementing mobile solutions for mobile workforce and building Tech Competencies

#### SR MANAGER & ARCHITECT | WIPRO TECHNOLOGIES | JULY 2005 - OCT 2008

• Played various Leadership roles in Product Engineering group, set up & managed a team to support <u>Avaya Devconnect Program</u>, which comprised of collaborating with third party application developers & integrators to develop & test applications using various Avaya products & services. Hands-on expert in J2ME application development & involved in prototyping mobile products & solutions for various customers

#### DEVELOPER | IBM SOFTWARE LABS | NOV 1999 - JUN 2005

- Aug 2003 June 2005 Was part of IBM Pervasive Computing team responsible for developing WebSphere Client Technology Micro Edition (WCTME) products on various handheld/mobile platforms. I was responsible for designing & implementing MIDP Application Management Software (AMS) on Palm V5 platform & later porting it to Windows Mobile 2005 & embedded Linux platform
- Nov 1999 July 2003 Led the "Java Technology Centre" (JTC) AIX/Linux team that was responsible for developing, maintaining & enhancing IBM Java Virtual Machine (JVM) on AIX, Linux, Solaris & Z O/S platforms.

#### DEVELOPER | WIPRO GLOBAL R&D | MARCH 1998 - OCT 1999

 Supported various Ethernet Products on Tandem (now HP) Non-Stop platform – TLAM (Tandem LAN Access Method) and was responsible for enhancing features specific to Dual Ethernet Fault Tolerance. Responsibilities included fixing reported bugs, scoping & implementing customer requested enhancements and planning service releases with thorough QA

## **Education**

#### BACHELOR'S IN ENGINEERING | BANGALORE UNIVERSITY

- · First Class with Distinction in Computer Science Engineering
- · Siddaganga Institute of Technology (SIT), Tumkur

#### **Certifications**

- · CNCF Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) Certificate ID LF-xeuld8wz19
- · CNCF Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD) Certificate ID LF-55bv7mz0mv
- · Scrum Alliance Certified ScrumMaster® (CSM) MEMBER: 000303320 (Not renewed)